See it early. Avoid the mob.
Jane Austen's Mafia! is a comedy, crime film directed by Jim Abrahams.
After growing up poor in Salmonella, Vincenzo Cortino installs himself as
the preeminent, if bumbling, Mafia don of the New World.
But now he must pass on power to one of his two sons: either
level-headed veteran Anthony or vituperative loose cannon Joey.
Anthony Cortino, played by Jay Mohr.
Joey Cortino, played by Billy Burke.
Diane Steen, played by Christina Applegate.
Pepper Gianini, played by Pamela Gidley.
Sophia, played by Olympia Dukakis.
Vincenzo Cortino, played by Lloyd Bridges.
Mafia!, also known as Jane Austen's Mafia!, is a 1998 American crime parody film directed by Jim Abrahams and
starring Jay Mohr, Lloyd Bridges (in one of his final films), Olympia Dukakis and Christina Applegate.
It was Abrahams’ final directorial effort before his death in 2024.
The film spoofs Francis Ford Coppola's Godfather series and various
other mafia films, notably Martin Scorsese's Casino (1995).
It also parodies films in other genres, ranging from Forrest
Gump to Il Postino and The English Patient.
In the film, a Korean War veteran avenges an
assassination attempt on his crime boss father.
The veteran subsequently manages a casino in Las Vegas,
until surviving another assassination attempt.
He sets out to gain vengeance, and to regain the love of his ex-girlfriend.
By that point his girlfriend had been elected as the President of the United States,
and he has to convince her to postpone her plans for world peace.
The film explores themes of escape, italy, sicily, italy, gangster, postman.
The tone is lighthearted.